<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>saske je cmaci</title>
    <description>I am setting up this blog to collect my thoughts</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 21:41:48 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 21:41:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tales of a lost passport!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is as written on 8th January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I got my first grad school interview selection. As you might be able to guess, grad school applications are a stressful procedure, and I was quite relieved to have gotten an interview call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool people from EPFL were flying me over to Lausanne, Switzerland for the interview. Since it was one of my top choices, I was ecstatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I had to apply for a visa. There was just one month between the time I got the invitation and the dates I was flying. Being me, I was exteremely anxious. Will I get a Visa, will I get it in time? So I had my tickets booked, collected all the paperwork needed and sat down to book a Visa Appointment at VFS, Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, since it was holiday season, to be precise it was 22nd December, nearly christmas and new years, so there were few working days at offices. I was going home on 27th, after a stressful semester. Sadly, I couldn’t get an appointment in Bangalore for the only worjing day when I was in Bangalore, which was 23rd. I was reaching home at Nasik on 27th December and I managed to book an appointment at Mumbai for 28th December. So Yay!! One entire day of my precious time off wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application process went quite smoothly. Since I was not sure, I would be able to collect my passport in Mumbai, I had it couriered to my Department at IISc. On 31st morning, I recieved a call, from Bluedart saying I had a delivery and they wanted to know exactly where they should come. Since its a passport, it has to be delivered to in person, either to the person whose passport it is, or some authorized person who has a letter and the counterfoil from VFS which acknowledges the recipt. So I told them that I was not in Bangalore and would be returning on 7th, and asked them to schedule the delivery on 7th. They said they would do it. (I was a bit surprised as they normally cannot keep a passport with them for more than 7 days, but I was glad they were keeping it with them.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 7th morning, I woke up and went to Bluedart office at 10am. I told the reception lady that I was there for my passport and she practially yelled at me for coming on the seventh day. I told her the story, and then she asked me for the tracking number of the package. From VFS, I had just recieved a message saying they had shipped my passport, but they hadn’t given me a tacking number, I had been surprized, but I didn’t know how it worked, so I said whatever. So I told her I didn’t have a tracking number. She glared at me, made faces and then asked me for my passport number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idiot that I am, I didn’t know my passport number. I also wasn’t carrying anything which had that number written down. I didn’t have internet on my phone. Also the pdf copy in my phone could not be opened because I hadn’t installed a pdf reader. Frustrated, I walked back to my hostel room and walked back to Bluedart office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, she put the tracking in the system, checked in her office and said they had my passport, but they couldn’t give it to me there, but had to deliver it at the address. This was 11:30 am and I was really frustrated, I had already wasted half a day chasing this document. So in the afternoon I expected to get a call at some point. I went to UG department office twice in the afternoon, but it had not been delivered. I finally gave up, and went to their office again, at 5 pm, when the office closes. They said they couldn’t reach their deliveryboy as his phone was off. Now all sort of silly scenarios started going through my mind. The pessimist that I am, I was freaking out. They said they’d definitely make the delivery today and that I should leave my contact details with them. I did that and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they didn’t call me by 19:30, I went back to them and demanded answers. They showed me a stamp of the UG office with a sign on it and said it has been delivered. Now, normally, one would be relieved at this point. But truely, this was the moment I freaked out the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, the way parcels for people are collected in the UG department in IISc is amazing. They have a table, on which there are 2 trays. Any parcel that comes is kept in one of these trays. There is also a notebook and a pen kept. Whenever a parcel arrives, they sign for it, collect it and keep it in one of these trays. When you pick up the parcel, you just take it from this table and sign your name in the notebook with a brief description of the parcel. Which means, there is bascially no record of who took which parcel etc. This normally works out well as anything important is never delivered to office and if the office knows its an important document, they refuse to collect it. But this asshole delivery guy hadn’t called me. He just gave the passport in the hands of someone at the office and didn’t even bother to ask for a counterfoil. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am just hoping that nobody has taken it until I can reach the office next morning when it opens. Next morning, at 10 am I go to office, and my worst fears are true! The parcel is not there. I show the people in the office a photograph of the reciept that Bluedart guys showed me. They said it was colleced by this one guy who had not showed up at office yet and asked me to come back in half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half an hour later, I went there. The guy who supposedly collected it is there and he says “I kept the parcel in one of the trays.” Then he checks this notebook. It has my name and the description of the package “VFS” written on it, but no sign. He says you have taken it “see”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the last things you want to hear. Then one of the ladies at the office says she saw two people collect parcels sometime after 5 pm. She tells me the name of one and a brief description of the other. So I called the first guy. His phone was not reachable and his room was locked. WOW. I try to figure out who the second one is, and after a few calls, I find him. He says he picked up the parcel, saw it was from VFS, and told handed it over to the first guy to give it to me immediately as we lived in the same hostel. YAY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, I just want my fucking passport in my fucking hand and I just don’t fucking care about anything anymore. I went to the first guy’s lab and see if he is there. He isn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that is the story till now as I write this. I think my friend should have the passport with him. I have emailed him, called him, messaged him, left a message for him with his labmates and a close friend of his. And I am just exhausted. Just completely exhausted. Lets see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Well, all’s well that ends well. Finally I could reach his phone a couple of hours later and got it from him. I was so relieved. But life, it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/life/Tales-of-nearly-lost-Passport.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/life/Tales-of-nearly-lost-Passport.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First post!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now I can strike an item off my new years resolutions list. Not that I have a list. Not that this was a big item. I just started a blog. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the easy part though. Creating a blog is barely the hard part. The hard part is to write regularly, and about things one cares about. Lets see how that goes. I plan to use this blog to keep track of things I do in life, my thoughts about the current events and write a bit about science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite happy with this jekyll based blog hosted on github. I mean, editing using a text editor, version control, and free hosting with unlimited customization ability. What more can one ask for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess this is a good enough begining. More actual content to follow soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/life/First-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/life/First-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
